Guide to the Robert A. Hill Collection, 1890-2014 RL.10993
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Robert A. Hill Collection
1890-2014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture
Hill, Robert A., 1943-
RL.10993
755 Linear Feet
The Robert A. Hill Collection covers the period of 1800 to 2014 and documents Hill's research, writing, and publications about Marcus Garvey's life and work and the founding of the Universal Negro Improvement Association (UNIA), as well as Hill's many other projects. Items in the collection include research material assembled by Hill, writings by and about Garvey, manuscripts, correspondence, printed material, clippings, microfilm, photographs, video and sound recordings, and objects. Series 1-4 contain the production papers of the Marcus Garvey Papers Project: American Volumes (AM), African Volumes (AF), Caribbean Volumes (CA), and Project Administration (PA). Hill's other projects and writings are included in Series 5-6 as Other Works by Robert A. Hill (OW) and Hill Personal (HP). The remaining Series 7-10 consists of Microfilm (MF), Primary Sources (PS), Research (RE), and the unprocessed Jamaica (J). The collection was acquired by the John Hope Franklin Research Center in 2015.
Arrangement
Robert A. Hill Collection (RAHC) is arranged into 10 series: 1. American Volumes Subjects and Drafts. 2. African Volumes Subjects and Drafts. 3. Caribbean Volumes Subjects and Drafts. 4. Project Administration. 5. Other Works by Robert A. Hill. 6. Robert A. Hill Personal. 7. Microfilm. 8. Primary Sources. 9. Research. 10. Jamaica.
The records are arranged in ten series, each of which have been further arranged into subseries. The contents of each series or subseries are arranged hierarchically to reflect Hill's order, then alphabetically, chronologically or numerically. Each of these series may contain digital media as well.
Scope and Contents
The major emphasis of the Hill Collection is The Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers, a series of publications that Hill edited for over thirty years that compile more than 30,000 documents highlighting the influence and accomplishments of Garvey and the UNIA. The process of compiling the twelve volumes is reflected in Hill's collection of research materials from manuscripts, photocopies of microfilm and original sources, newspaper clippings, annotated printed materials, photographs, scholar's correspondence, FBI records, and annotated drafts from U.S. and international archives, universities, and libraries. The bulk of the research materials are reproductions. Original materials can be found in the Primary Sources (PS) series.
The Other Works series contains Hill's personal papers, university-related materials and correspondence, general research, presentations, and other writings. These documents include Hill's historical editions such as Marcus Garvey's The Black Man: A Monthly Magazine of Negro Thought and Opinion; Cyril V. Briggs' The Crusader; George S. Schuyler's Black Empire and Ethiopian Stories; and The FBI's RACON: Racial Conditions in the United States during World War II.
Biographical / Historical
Robert Abraham Henry Hill, a Jamaican by birth, upbringing and education, is Research Professor of History at the University of California, Los Angeles, where he has been a member of the faculty since 1977-1978. He was born in Jamaica on October 27, 1943 and was educated at the Jesuit high-school for boys in Jamaica, St. George's College. He is the editor in chief of The Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Papers, a multi-volume letterpress edition of the papers of the largest organized movement of blacks in history. Today, he is renowned internationally as the preeminent scholar of Marcus Garvey and his movement. In addition, he is the literary executor of the Estate of C.L.R. James.
Professor Hill left Jamaica to study law at The London School of Economics, University of London, but switched to the study of politics. After leaving London, he moved to Canada, where he earned a B.A. in Political Science from University College, University of Toronto. During this time, Professor Hill was one of the founding members of the Committee on West Indian Affairs and the founder of the C.L.R. James Study Circle. Both organizations were to play an important part in the growth of political consciousness among young West Indian students; included among them were students such as Rosie Douglas, Anne Cools, Alfie Roberts, Tim Hector, Franklyn Harvey, and many others, several of whom went on to play a significant role in the political awakening in the Caribbean. Upon graduating in 1967, Professor Hill returned to Jamaica where he became involved in the movement for Black Power, serving as the editor of The Abeng, the main organ of the movement while studying at the University of the West Indies, Mona. It was here that he commenced his life-long scholarly pursuit of the story of Marcus Garvey and the UNIA, receiving a M.Sc. in Government for his thesis on Marcus Garvey and Crown Colony Government in Jamaica.
Professor Hill moved to America in 1970 to continue this research. Prior to his appointment at UCLA, Professor Hill served as a senior research fellow at the Institute of the Black World in Atlanta, Georgia, and taught at Dartmouth College and Northwestern University.
The University of California Press and Duke University Press have published fourteen volumes of The Marcus Garvey and UNIA Papers. In addition, Professor Hill has collected and published several other volumes of historical materials, including Cyril Valentine Briggs's The Crusader Magazine (1918-1921), Marcus Garvey's Black Man Magazine (1933-1939), and George Schuyler's Black Empire and Ethiopian Stories. One of the achievements of Professor Hill's research has been on the life of Leonard P. Howell, one of the prophets of the early Rastafari movement in the nineteen-thirties in Jamaica, as well as the lives of other key Rastafari and Back-to-Africa figures. In addition, Professor Hill has published influential essays on C.L.R. James, Walter Rodney, and George Beckford of Jamaica, in addition to essays on such pioneering Pan-African figures as W.E.B. DuBois, Dr. J. Albert Thorne of Guyana and Chief Charles Sam of the Gold Coast.
Conditions Governing Access
Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Contact Research Services in advance to request production of use copies.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection contains electronic records that may need to be reformatted. Access copies of electronic records must be accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services for access.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Robert Hill Collection was acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2015.
Biographical / Historical
Chronology
1887 Marcus Garvey was born in Jamaica
1923 Marcus Garvey's mail fraud trial
1943 Robert Abraham Henry Hill born
1975 The Rastafari Bible: The Essential Collection of Sacred Writings That Inspired a Black Liberation Movement, Robert A. Hill, published Marcus Garvey: The Black Man; a Monthly Magazine of Negro Thought and Opinion: 1933 thru 1939 (1-4), edited by Marcus Garvey and Robert A. Hill, published
1978 Marcus Garvey and the Federal Prosecution Efforts, 1918—1927 (Paper presented at the National Archives Conference, Washington, D.C.)
1979 Afro-American Culture and society. A CAAS monograph series. Ed. Robert A. Hill, published
1983 The Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers, Volume I: 1826-August 1919 published The Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers, Volume II: 27 August 1919--31 August 1920 published
1984 The Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers, Volume III: September 1920-August 1921 published
1985 The Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers, Volume IV: September 1921-September 1922 published The Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers, Volume VI: September 1924-December 1927 published
1973 Editor, with Richard Small, "The Teachings of Robert E. Rumble: Jamaican Peasant Leader," in Education and Black Struggle: Notes from the Colonized World. Harvard Education Review Monograph, NO. 2
1987 Pan-African Biography published The Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers, Volume V: September 1922-August 1924 published The Crusader, Cyril V. Briggs, editor, edited with a new introduction and index by Robert A. Hill published Marcus Garvey Life and Lessons: A Centennial Companion to the Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers, by Marcus Garvey and Robert A. Hill published Marcus Garvey: The Centennial Exhibition, Schomburg Center
1991 The Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers, Volume VII: December 1927-August 1940 published Black Empire; George S. Schuyler, writing as Samuel I. Brooks; foreword by John A. Williams; edited, with an afterword, by Robert A. Hill & R. Kent Rasmussen published
1994 Ethiopian Stories; George S. Schuyler; compiled and edited with an introduction by Robert A. Hill published
1995 The Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers, Vol. IX: Africa for the Africans June 1921-December 1922 published The FBI's RACON: Racial Conditions in the United States during World War II published
2001 Look For Me in the Whirlwind, by Firelight Media for PBS' series "American Experience"
2006 The Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers, Vol. X: Africa for the Africans, 1923-1945 published
2008 Marcus Garvey: The Centennial Exhibition, The Schomburg Center Traveling Exhibition Program
2011 The Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers, Volume XI: The Caribbean Diaspora, 1910–1920 published
2014 The Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers, Volume XII: The Caribbean Diaspora, 1920-1921 published
2016 The Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers, Volume XIII: The Caribbean Diaspora, 1921-1922 published
Conditions Governing Access
The African Volumes (AF) Series is closed to researcher access except by permission of the curator of the John Hope Franklin Research Center. Researchers can request permission to use this series through the Research Services Dept. Materials specifically related to the unpublished Volume 8 of the Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers (held within the African Volumes series) are restricted to reading room use only, with no reproductions. This restriction expires in 2025 or until the volume is published, whichever comes first.
Africa -- History -- 20th century; African American intellectuals -- Correspondence; African American political activists; African American women -- Political activity; African Americans -- History; African diaspora -- 20th century; England -- History -- 20th century; Jamaica -- History; Racism -- United States -- History; Segregation -- United States -- History; United States -- Politics and government -- 20th century; Black nationalism -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Black separatism -- 20th century; Blacks -- 20th century; Caribbean Area -- 20th century; Rastafari movement; John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture; White, Elinor; University of California, Los Angeles; African Methodist Episcopal Church; African Orthodox Church; Afro Athlican Constructive Church; Briggs, Cyril V. (Cyril Valentine); Davis, Henrietta; Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1868-1963; Garvey, Amy Ashwood, approximately 1895-1969; Garvey, Marcus, 1887-1940; Garvey, Amy Jacques; National Endowment for the Humanities; Pickens, William, 1881-1954; Marley, Bob; Rogers, Robert Athlyi; Schuyler, George S. (George Samuel), 1895-1977; United Fruit Company; Universal Negro Improvement Association; United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation; United States. National Historical Publications and Records Commission; Sam, Alfred C. (Alfred Charles); International Peacemakers Association
- American Volumes (AM), 1865-2007 and undated; 1; 37 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains research and preparation materials used in publishing Robert Hill's Marcus Garvey and Universal Negro Improvement Association Papers, American Volumes I-VII (1846-1940). The series chronicles Garvey's life in Jamaica, his travels through the Caribbean, the founding and evolution of the Universal Negro Improvement Association (UNIA) in the United States, and his fraud conviction, deportation to Jamaica, and eventual death in England. This series also includes Hill's Annotated and Indexed Subjects for the unpublished Volume VIII of the series, which covers Africa.
  - Annotated and Indexed Subjects, 1
    The Annotated and Indexed Subjects subseries consists of alphabetized subject files on research topics compiled by Robert Hill. It includes Hill's annotated and indexed photocopies of articles from Garvey's newspapers: The Negro World, The Black Man, and his monthly magazine The Blackman. Annotated photocopies of microfilm, printed material, and transcripts from newspapers covering biographic information on public figures involved with government policy, business operations, and activist teachings and activities can also be found here. This subseries contains Garvey's speeches and writings from his publications as well as those of his contemporaries, such as W.E.B. Du Bois, Henrietta Vinton Davis, and William Pickens. Also included are documentation from the UNIA concerning its divisions and finances, the Black Star Line and its officers, the Bureau of Investigation (later the Federal Bureau of Investigation) on surveillance of Garvey, and Garvey's mail fraud trial.
    Notes on book elements such as acknowledgements, annotation lists, appendices, bibliographies and biographies, duplicate and excluded documents, introductions, and lists of mentioned individuals are in this subseries as well.
    - Abyssinian Prince, 1921 Jan (Box AM1)
    - Abyssinian Baptist Church, 1921, 1923, 1984 (Box AM1)
    - Acknowledgments, Vol. I, undated (Box AM1)
    - Acknowledgments, Vol. IV, 1983 (Box AM1)
    - Adee, A.A., 1924 (Box AM1)
    - Adee, Alvey A., 1920, 1924, 1949 (Box AM1)
    - Adegboyega, Edun, 1922, 1970 (Box AM1)
    - Aderhold, Warden A.C., 1931 Jun 11 (Box AM1)
    - Ahern, Patrice J., undated (Box AM1)
    - Alexander the Great, 1901, 1963 (Box AM1)
    - Alien Act, 1917, 1933 Jun (Box AM1)
    - Alonen, Gustave, 1919 (Box AM1)
    - Alsop, John T., 1973, 1985 (Box AM1)
    - Amos, James A. - Garvey arrest and appeal, 1924-1926 (Box AM1)
    - Anderson, James H., 1931, 1976, 1980 (Box AM1)
    - Annotated documents, 1923 (Box AM1)
    - Annotated proofs, 1993-1994 (Box AM1)
    - Annotation list, undated (Box AM1)
    - Annotation list - Bobby's, undated (Box AM1)
    - Arius, 1870, 1963 (Box AM1)
    - Armstrong, George A., 1935 Mar 27, 1971 Jan 2 (Box AM1)
    - Armstrong, Harry G. (British Consul General, New York) (Box AM1)
      Savannah Tribune
    - Armstrong, Henry Closter, undated (Box AM1)
    - Ashburner, Charles E., 1922, 1932, 1980 (Box AM1)
    - Asquith, Herbert, 1928 (Box AM1)
    - Asthma cigarettes, 1973 (Box AM1)
    - Ausin, Junius Caesar, 1919-1981 (Box AM1)
    - Austin, Junius C., 1923 May (Box AM1)
    - Bagnall, Robert W., 1922 (Box AM1)
    - Baker, Newton Diehl, 1920-1921, 1925, 1980 (Box AM1)
    - Balboa - League of Struggle for Negro Rights, 1922 (Box AM1)
    - Balch, Emily, 1935 Aug 31 (Box AM1)
    - Ballentine, Claudius M., 1935, 1948 (Box AM1)
    - Ballinger, Commissioner J.G., 1913, 1924, 1981 (Box AM1)
    - Barbusse, Henri, 1935 (Box AM1)
    - Barett Lennard, Fiennes, undated (Box AM1)
    - Bass, Mrs. Charlotta, 1980 (Box AM1)
    - Basuma, W.S., 1984 Jan 4-1984 Feb 2 (Box AM1)
    - Bayne, John G., undated (Box AM1)
    - BBC - Lord Reith, 1963, 1971-1975 (Box AM1)
    - Beasley, Charles W., 1940 Apr 24 (Box AM1)
    - Beck, William Hopkins, 1922 (Box AM1)
    - Beecher, Henry W., 1887 (Box AM1)
    - Belize - officials, etc., 1985 Jul 10 (Box AM1)
    - Bell, William T., undated (Box AM1)
    - Bentley, Dr. Charles E., 1969, 1981 (Box AM1)
    - Berry O'Kelly, 1915-1976 (Box AM1)
    - Beveridge, Ray, 1921 (Box AM1)
    - Bibliography, 1915, 1925, 1936 (Box AM1)
    - Biograpical index - Vol. III, undated (Box AM1)
    - Bishop, Mr. J.T., 1919, 1920 (Box AM1)
    - Black boycott white businesses, 1923-1924 (Box AM1)
    - Black christ, 1924-1926 (Box AM1)
    - Black Cross Navigation and Trading Co. finances, 1923 Sep-1926 Feb (Box AM1)
    - Black Man of Sorrows, 1924, 1925; 2 folders (Box AM1)
    - Black Star Line, annotated proof, 1922 (Box AM1)
    - Black Star Line officers, 1919-1921 (Box AM1)
    - Blackman publication & Black Man 1930s, 1929-1931 (Box AM1)
    - Blacks and venereal disease, 1923-1924 (Box AM1)
    - Blacks in Democratic and Republican Party Politics, 1941 Jul (Box AM1)
    - Blease, Coleman Livingston, undated (Box AM1)
    - Blue Vein and Colonial Society, 1980-1984 (Box AM1)
    - Bose, Rash Behari, 1925 Dec (Box AM1)
    - Bourne, C.S., 1920 Aug-1923 Sep (Box AM1)
    - Boyd, Rev. Henry Allen, 1910, 1959, 1980 (Box AM1)
    - Bracken, Edward, 1985 Oct, 1929 Jun (Box AM1)
    - Braithwaite, William Stanley, 1918-1919, 1939, 1969 (Box AM1)
    - Bridges, Horace, 1916-1917 (Box AM1)
    - Briggs, Bertha F., 1918 (Box AM1)
    - Brisbane, Arthur, 1936 Dec, 1931 Jan 26 (Box AM1)
    - British economy and Caribbean slavery, 1987 (Box AM1)
    - British plan colonization of Jews, 1937-1939, 1978 (Box AM1)
    - Brooks, Rev. Dr. J.D., 1890, 1921-1922 (Box AM1)
    - Brooks, J.G., 1966 (Box AM1)
    - Brough, Gov., 1865, 1909, 1980 (Box AM1)
    - Brown, Rev. Ethelred, 1923 (Box AM1)
    - Brown, Edward G., 1976, 1980 (Box AM1)
    - Brown, John, undated (Box AM1)
    - Brown, Roscoe Conklin, 1976, 1980 (Box AM1)
    - Brown, Rev. Willis W., 1918, 1969 (Box AM1)
    - Bryan, W.J. at Cristobol Colon, 1911 Nov-Dec (Box AM1)
    - Buck, Prof., 1920 Mar 27 (Box AM1)
    - Bull Steam Ship Line, 1922-1926 (Box AM1)
    - Bullock, Matthew, 1909, 1927, 1981 (Box AM1)
    - Burdon, J.A., 1928 (Box AM1)
    - Bureau of Investigation - coverage of Garvey, 1920-1921 (Box AM1)
    - Burroughs, Nannie H., 1910, 1916, 1980 (Box AM1)
    - Buteo, Bertha J., undated (Box AM1)
    - Butler, President Nicholas Murray, 1927 Jan (Box AM1)
    - Byles, William Pollard, 1929 (Box AM1)
    - Cahan, Abraham, 1951 (Box AM1)
    - Cahill, John, 1939 Jul (Box AM1)
    - Callis, H.J., 1908, 1919, 1955 (Box AM1)
    - Caminetti, Anthony, undated (Box AM1)
    - Campbell, M.L., 1916, 1922, 1924 (Box AM1)
    - Campbell, Thomas M., 1979 (Box AM1)
    - Canadian Ambassador to U.S., 1921 Feb (Box AM1)
    - Canadian Expositions, 1937, 1940 (Box AM1)
    - Cannon, George E., 1925, 1950, 1976 (Box AM1)
    - Cannon, James P., 1926 Jul (Box AM1)
    - Cardwell, Dr. David Thomas, undated (Box AM1)
    - Carey, Rev. A.J., 1920, 1923, 1972 (Box AM1)
    - Carr, Wilbur J., 1942 Jun 27 (Box AM1)
    - Carranza, President Venustiano - Mexico, undated (Box AM1)
    - Carter, Miss Jeannette, undated (Box AM1)
    - Carter, Marshall, 1981 (Box AM1)
    - Carver, George Washington, undated (Box AM1)
    - Casement, Sir Roger David, 1972 (Box AM1)
    - Casha, William, 1937 (Box AM1)
    - Castle William R., 1963 (Box AM1)
    - Cavell, Edith, 1915, 1961, 1963 (Box AM1)
    - Cellar, Emanuel, 1926, 1927, 1986 (Box AM1)
    - Cheek, E.A.P., 1884 (Box AM1)
    - Chicago and New York City legislators, 1919-1924 (Box AM1)
    - Chinese Delegate, Statement of, 1921 (Box AM1)
    - Chronology, Vol. VI, 1925 Oct 31 (Box AM1)
    - Church, R.R., 1908, 1952-1953, 1980 (Box AM1)
    - Churchman, The, 1924 (Box AM1)
    - Claparede, Rene, undated (Box AM1)
    - Clayton, Nettie, 1981 (Box AM1)
    - Clinton, Bishop George W., 1895, 1902, 1976 (Box AM1)
    - Coker, James, 1917, 1981 (Box AM1)
    - Colban, Erik, 1956 (Box AM1)
    - Colby, Bainbridge, 1925, 1937, 1950 (Box AM1)
    - Coleman, Bessie, 1922 Aug (Box AM1)
    - Collet, Wilfred, undated (Box AM1)
    - Colonies in AF more rights: response to UNIA, 1962-1972 (Box AM1)
    - Connelly, Albert S., 1927 (Box AM1)
    - Coolidge, Calvin, undated (Box AM1)
    - Coolidge Jr., Calvin, 1924 (Box AM1)
    - Corcoran, W.W., 1933 Dec-1962 Sep (Box AM1)
    - Council of Trent, 1973 (Box AM1)
    - Couqlin, Captain, undated (Box AM1)
    - Cove, Ernest J., 1935 (Box AM2)
    - Cox, Ernest Sevier, 1914 Jun-1986 May (Box AM2)
    - Craigen, J.A., 1927 (Box AM2)
    - Crain, Thomas C.T., 1925, 1942, 1980 (Box AM2)
    - Cranston, Rev., 1981 (Box AM2)
    - Crawford, Lee, 1942, 1980 (Box AM2)
    - Crim, John W.H., 1933 Jul (Box AM2)
    - Cromwell, Oliver, undated (Box AM2)
    - Crosswaite, F.W., 1920, 1940, 1980 (Box AM2)
    - Crowley, Karl A., undated (Box AM2)
    - Crummell, Alexander, 1895-1980 (Box AM2)
    - Crusader on the Black Star Line, 1921 Oct (Box AM2)
    - Cuban Uprising of 1912, 1913, 1922 (Box AM2)
    - Cumberbatch, George (Allen), undated (Box AM2)
    - Cummings, Homer S., 1956 Sep (Box AM2)
    - Cunard, Nancy, 1932, 1933-1965, 1970 (Box AM2)
    - Cundall, Herbert M., 1928 Sep (Box AM2)
    - Curley, C.B., 1928, 1929 (Box AM2)
    - Curran, Henry, 1921, 1925, 1966 (Box AM2)
    - Curzon, Earl - of Kedleston, 1925 Mar 20, 1963 (Box AM2)
    - Daily Worker on Garvey and Klan, 1924 (Box AM2)
    - Daly, John, 1948 Feb 28, 1980 Jun 5 (Box AM2)
    - Dancy, Benny, 1923 (Box AM2)
    - Dancy, Count, 1919-1920 (Box AM2)
    - Daniel, Rev. E.V., 1922 (Box AM2)
    - Danton, George Jacques, undated (Box AM2)
    - Darling, Roy A., 1927 Mar 29 (Box AM2)
    - Darwin, Charles Robert, (1809-1882), 1963 (Box AM2)
    - Daughterty, Harry, 1927 Feb-1928 Jun (Box AM2)
    - Daughton, R.H., 1944-1958 (Box AM2)
    - Davis, Benjamin Jefferson, 1945 Oct 29 (Box AM2)
    - Davis, Henrietta Vinton, 1883-1984; 2 folders (Box AM2)
    - Davis, James, 1925 (Box AM2)
    - Davis, Ambassador John W., 1955, 1980 (Box AM2)
    - Dean, W.H., 1953 (Box AM2)
    - Debs, Eugene Victor, 1926-1927 (Box AM2)
    - Deleted documents - Vol. VI, Vol. VII, 1925-1926, 1929-1940; 2 folders (Box AM2)
    - Delisser, H.G., 1920 Sep-1968 (Box AM2)
    - De Mena, M.L.T., 1925-1932 (Box AM2)
    - DePriest, Oscar, 1928 Nov 17, 1960-1976 (Box AM2)
    - Deschanel, Paul Eugene Lonis, undated (Box AM2)
    - Detroit UNIA Division, 1923, 1932 (Box AM2)
    - Devalera, Eamon, 1930 Aug-Oct, 1961 (Box AM2)
    - Devoy, John, 1928 Oct (Box AM2)
    - Disraeli, Benjamin, 1963 (Box AM2)
    - Domingo on Marcus Garvey, undated (Box AM2)
    - Dobs, General (Alfred A. Dodds), 1922, 1969, 1976 (Box AM2)
    - Donnelly, Horace James, 1934 Sep (Box AM2)
    - Donovan, William J., 1959 (Box AM2)
    - Dossen, James J., 1924 (Box AM2)
    - Douglass, Joseph Henry (1871-1935), 1969, 1980 Jul 9 (Box AM2)
    - Douglass, Dr. Joseph Henry, Dr., 1966 (Box AM2)
    - Dowie, John Alexander, 1907 Mar 10, 1921-1962 (Box AM2)
    - Driver, Rev. Edie, 1978 (Box AM2)
    - Drummond, Eric, 1951-1960 (Box AM2)
    - DuBois background, 1925 (Box AM2)
    - DuBois, W.E.B., annotated transcribed documents, 1914, 1918-1919; 4 folders (Box AM2)
    - DuBois, W.E.B., annotated transcribed documents, 1997 May 5; 3 folders (Box AM2)
    - Duchatellier, Marie, undated (Box AM3)
    - Dufaubourg, Club, 1928 Oct 27-1928 Nov 10 (Box AM3)
    - Duffy, Paul, 1948 Aug 6 (Box AM3)
    - Duke of Devonshire, 1938 (Box AM3)
    - Dumas, Alexandre Dary, 1961, 1963 (Box AM3)
    - Duncan, Luther N., 1947 (Box AM3)
    - Duncan, Colonel Otis B., 1974 (Box AM3)